

# **MARIA SOROKINA**

Frontend developer Russia. Ready to relocate

#### **CONTACT ME**

+7 (909) 138-06-66 mashasorokina@inbox.ru LinkedIn: @bijou743 GitHub: @bijou743

#### **LANGUAGES**

Russian, English

### **Summary**

I work in web programming more than 10 years. I have 1 year experience as PHP-developer, 3 years experience in Java-development as employee and 7 years experience of web development in my own business. At the beginnig of 2022 I've decided to change my career and work as frontend developer. During my career I've been engaged in the development of new web applications from scratch, as well as working with existing systems with a large set of legacy code. With a curiosity to understand new technologies and approaches, I am ready for any task and complexity.

#### **Tools**







CSS



SASS/SCSS



**Tailwind** 



Bootstrap



**JavaScript** 



**VueJS** 



NuxtJS



React



**TypeScript** 



Webpack















Zeplin

## **Experience**

2014-2022 Self-employed
Wheelko - boardgames shop

In the fall of 2014 I opened a board games shop in Kirov. The store has been successfully operating for a little over 7 years and in January 2022 I closed it. During this time I performed a huge range of duties: I was a shop assistant, was engaged in hiring staff process, led social networks, selected assortment, was engaged in marketing.

Moreover I developed and supported a website for my shop, both backend and frontend. I created a full-fledged online store with choise of delivery method and online payment for orders. Also part of the site was a CRM system, developed by me for the needs of the store.

Using technologies: Java, OpenCms, HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, Spring Roo, PostgreSQL, Maven

# 2011 - 2014 Full stack developer ITDT I td. itdt.ru

When I worked for ITDT my responsibilities included reworking with the company's existing projects (web applications, desktop applications) and creating web applications from scratch.

One of the projects in which creation I took part from scratch is the website for the Contemporary Art Museum Erarta erarta.com. The website was developed based on OpenCms using Spring Roo. In 2014 I quit from ITDT and became an entrepreneur. In my independent job I used skills and experience gained while working in this company.

Using technologies: Java, OpenCms, HTML, CSS, JSP, JavaScript, jQuery, Spring Roo, PostgreSQL, Maven

2010 - 2011 Web developer Software center pbprog.ru

I started to work in Software center between the 4th and 5th year of study at the university. During the work I created a company website on the 1C-Bitrix platform. My responsibilities included developing the site structure, setting up the necessary modules, forms, adding content to the site and customizing existing 1C-Bitrix modules.

Using technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, 1C-Bitrix

# **Education**

2006-2011 Vyatka State University

Master's degreen in "Informatics in econimics". Diploma with honors.

# **Hobbies**

In addition to programming I love cinema, boardgames, cooperative computer games, quizzes, music and travel.